Under your course's Manage Settings,
cue-2
scroll down to Curriculum and
click into the Scheduling & Assessment
cue-3
Settings. Now we see a page with four tabs
of settings. In general, the Schedule tab
cue-4
lets you create a suggested course
timeline for students to follow. The
cue-5
Assessment Settings tab allows you to
configure each assessment item in more
cue-6
detail. The Student Expectations tab
enables you to set accommodations for
cue-7
individual students based on their needs.
Finally, Advanced Gating is for
cue-8
instructors who want more control over how
and when course materials become
cue-9
accessible. If you need help with Advanced
Gating, contact OLI Help at
cue-10
oli-help@cmu.edu. Let's start with the
Scheduling setting. Here you will see
cue-11
your course timeline laid out across
weeks. Each line here represents a unit of
cue-12
the course. Later, you will have an
adjustable schedule on this page. To start
cue-13
with, click Set Schedule. Select the day
you want to consider for that schedule,
cue-14
click Continue.
cue-15
If you choose Do Not Set Assessment Due
Dates, the system will not automatically
cue-16
assign any due dates. You will need to
manually set them later in the Assessment
cue-17
Setting view. If you choose Set Assessment
Due Dates According to the Sequence of
cue-18
Course Content, due dates will align with
where each assessment appears within a
cue-19
unit. For example, if an assessment is
placed halfway through a unit, its due
cue-20
date will also be scheduled halfway
through that unit's duration.
cue-21
If you choose Set Assessment Due Dates to
the End of Each Section, all assessments
cue-22
will be due at the end of their respective
units. So even if an assessment appears
cue-23
midway through that unit, its due date
will still be at the end of that unit.
cue-24
This option is the most commonly used. Now
you will see a Gantt-style timeline. Use
cue-25
Control plus minus or Command plus minus
to adjust the size of the content on the
cue-26
screen for the best view. You can view or
hide details of a unit by clicking the
cue-27
small black button or the Expand
All/Collapse All button. Length of each
cue-28
block represent the suggested time
duration of the unit, which is independent
cue-29
of assessment dates you set. They are
interactive and fully adjustable, meaning
cue-30
that you can move it or drag the ends to
change when a unit begins or ends. You can
cue-31
also search for a specific module or
topic using the search bar. By default,
cue-32
items under Unit are set to Suggested By
Dates. Suggested By Date is for keeping
cue-33
students on track, for example, with their
readings. While Due By Date is for
cue-34
scored/graded objects. You can change one
item's date into Hard Due Dates or
cue-35
In-Class Activity by clicking and editing
them on the bottom left-hand corner of the
cue-36
screen.
cue-37
The item will then change to a calendar or
group icon. You can also right-click a
cue-38
unit or item to remove it, adjust dates
with numeric input given selected units or
cue-39
assessment item, or drag and reposition
the task on the timeline.
cue-40
This gives you granular control over how
students pace themselves. Remember to
cue-41
click Save Changes after you are done. If
you want to preview the schedule from a
cue-42
student view, go back to the course Manage
Settings. Click Preview as Student to see
cue-43
what your learners will see. Recent items
will appear under Upcoming Agenda on the
cue-44
homepage, and the full schedule can be
viewed on the Schedule page.
cue-45
And that's the Scheduling tool. Remember,
you can change these settings at any time,
cue-46
even after the course has begun. In the
next video, we'll walk through the
cue-47
Assessment Settings.